Jennifer J. Chang

Email <u>missty82@gmail.com</u>
Portfolio <u>www.keepdreaming.me</u>

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/jennyj-chang/

Intro

I have over 7 years of experience in User Experience and Interaction Design for Android/iOS apps and responsive websites. I try to create simple, enjoyable, and inspiring user experience by practicing user-centered design principles basing on user needs and business goals. I enjoy working in a team environment with designers and developers.

Skill Summary

Design:

- User Experience Design
- Interaction Design
- Rapid Prototyping
- User Research
- Information Architect
- Usability Testing
- Design Thinking

Tools:

- Microsoft Office (ppt/xls/doc)
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe After Effects
- InVision, Axure, Marvel, Balsamiq, Asana
- Jira, Trello, Slack
- Arduino, etc.

Languages:

- HTML5/CSS3
- Android
- Korean, English, French

Experience

Chief Product Officer & Founding Member

Celuv · Daejeon · South Korea

June 2017 - March 2018

Celuv is a startup company with the vision to become the next generation entertainment agency. The company aims to help fans to stay updated with their favorite celebrities, and help agencies to manage the celebrities and their schedules. As the Chief Product Officer, I had the overall responsibility for the development of the Celuv mobile application and the Manager website.

- Responsible for developing Celuv mobile application (iOS) and its admin website
- Conducted user research through interviews and usability testing
- Created actionable and intuitive design flows by developing high fidelity wireframes

Major Project: Celuv · iOS application and manager website

Tools used: PowerPoint, Marvel, Sympli, XD, Jira, Slack, Photoshop, HTML, CSS

UX Designer & PM

 $Lucis \cdot Seoul \cdot South \ Korea$

August 2016 - December 2016

As Project Manager, I was in charge of overseeing the development of JusTrip, a travel app that ensures Chinese tourists traveling in Korea a safe and fun trip.

- Planned and implemented UX and marketing strategies for JusTrip
- Created business plan, user scenarios, flow charts, IA documents, wireframes, and interactive prototype
- Managed the project team, monitored the progress, and reported to stakeholders

Major Project: JusTrip · Android application and admin website

Tools used: PowerPoint, Axure, Asana, Trello, Slack

Director of User Experience

nblisscomz · Seoul · South Korea

August 2015 - March 2016

nblisscomz is a startup company with a goal to help users achieve their dreams. As the former founding member and Director of User Experience, I was responsible of the overall development of the WishingNote mobile app (Android/iOS) and the admin website and the management of designers and developers.

- Worked closely with designers and developers to create WishingNote mobile app (Android/iOS) and admin web
- Analyzed user data and created user scenarios, user flows, and IA documents
- Created actionable and intuitive design flows through high fidelity wireframes
- Designed and developed app landing page using a Bootstrap template
- Created pitch decks to use at several startup demo days and to pitch to VCs

Project: Wishingnote · iOS/Android application and admin website

Tools used: PowerPoint, Excel, Photoshop, Vegas, InVision, HTML, CSS

UX Designer & PM

Hong International · Seoul · South Korea

August 2013 - August 2015

- Responsible for developing and operating several websites and mobile applications of the company including itemshop (web), Phoenix app (Android/iOS) & website, and promotional websites (e.g. Summer Festival website)
- Worked closely with overseas sales team to plan and implement UX strategies that reflected country-specific individuality especially in Japan
- Produced flow charts, wireframes, and design specification focusing on maintaining a constant user experience across multiple channels (e.g. from game console to mobile app)
- Worked as project manager on several projects, working closely with designers, server/DB/web/app developers.

Major Projects: itemshop · responsive website, Phoenix · Android/iOS app and responsive website, other promotional websites

Tools used: PowerPoint, Excel, Photoshop, InVision

Business Planner & UX Designer

 $\mathsf{SQISoft} \cdot \mathsf{Seoul} \cdot \mathsf{South} \; \mathsf{Korea}$

December 2009 - May 2013

- Planned and created proposals for new business opportunities
- Created wireframes, designed user interface, and developed IVIC-M Android app for doctors and nurses and Health Note (IVIC-H) Android app for general users
- Gathered and analyzed user data through methods such as analytics reporting and task analysis, and created user stories, user flows and wireframes to redesign the hybrid mobile app and the responsive website of olleh to provide a better user experience
- Created UX and marketing strategies and promotional contents for olleh tv website
- Consulted and designed the UX for Samsung monitoring system focusing on providing a seamless and connected experience from wallboard to managers' individual PC monitors and mobile

 $\textbf{Major Projects:} \ olleh \ CS \cdot hybrid \ mobile \ app \ and \ website, \ olleh \ tv \cdot website, \ IVIC \ \& \ Health \ Note \cdot Android \ mobile \ app, \ Samsung \ Monitoring \ System$

Strategic Planning / Editor

 $\textbf{Statistics Korea} \cdot \textbf{Daejeon} \cdot \textbf{South Korea}$

May 2008 – December 2009

- Planned for the 3rd OECD World Forum on "Statistics, Knowledge and Policy" and the International Exhibition which attracted close to 2,000 from more than 100 different countries
- Translated and edited the materials for the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd OECD World Forum
- Responsible for the communication between OECD and Statistics Korea, regarding the invitations of speakers, agenda of the forum, and other related issues
- Oversaw the production work for the exhibition booth of the Statistics Korea
- Managed the progress work of the PCO company

Major Project: the third OECD World Forum and International Exhibition

Education

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology Master's Program in Entrepreneurship & Innovation / Knowledge Service Engineering Activities and Societies: Design Thinking Lab	2017 – 2018
Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Activities and Societies: Voluntary Service, Ski and Snowboard	2000 – 2007
INSA Lyon - Institut National des Sciences Appliquées de Lyon Exchange Student Programme, Informatique	2003 – 2004
American International School Vienna	1997 – 2000